

### Software Developer Vicente Paul Guerrero Lule

Mannsfelder Str. 1 – 50968 – Cologne viclule.github.io | vic.lule@googlemail.com | (+49) 176 32715017

Software Development, Machine Learning and Data Science. python, java, kotlin, aws, gitlab, docker, ci/cd, scrum, safe

### **Profile**

A science enthusiast with extensive experience in model, algorithm and software development. Eight years of experience, the last half of them focusing on python and java related languages for microservices and machine learning development, and deployment in the cloud.

TDD, scrum and solution-oriented describe my way of working. Equally effective in a team environment or as a lone specialist.

### Work Experience

5/2019 – Freelance Software Developer

Germany

 Python/Java/Kotlin Software development in the "Hello, Magenta" voice assistant project from **Deutsche Telekom.** (see pages 4 & 5) python, java, kotlin, NLP, microservices, gitlab, scrum, safe, ci/cd

6/2017 - 5/2019

Software Engineer - in the Intelligent Products team

Leybold GmbH, Cologne. (see pages 4 & 6)

- Design and development of a cloud-based data collection strategy from machines in the field and laboratories
- ❖ Machine learning models development and clustering analysis
- API development and documenting

python, pandas, numpy, sklearn, tensorflow, keras, flask, django, git, aws

9/2016 - 5/2017

Freelance Software Developer

Germany

- Software Development
- Development of Machine Vision applications

C#, MVTec Halcon

1/2013 - 8/2016

**Product Developer - Micro Assembly** 

Micro Automation, St. Leon-Rot

- Coordination with research institutions
  - Design and development of a software architecture for complex automation processes

11/2010 - 12/2012

Research Assistant in the Micro Production department

Fraunhofer-Institute for Production Technologies, Aachen

- Design and development of novel concepts for the high precision assembly of optical components
- Development of image-processing-based algorithms

09/2009 - 08/2010

Research Assistant (part time) in the Energy Efficient Buildings and Indoor Climate department

E.ON Energy Research Center, RWTH, Aachen

Development of control software for research setups

03/2008 – 09/2008	<ul> <li>Entry engineer in the Performance department</li> <li>General Electric, Advanced Turbomachinery Engineering Center,</li> <li>Queretaro, Mexico</li> <li>❖ Software development for the analysis of thermodynamic data</li> </ul>
Education ——	
09/2008 – 08/2010	Master of Science in Mechatronics, Fachhochschule Aachen (1,3), Aachen, Germany
07/2003 - 02/2008	<b>Mechanical Engineer, specialty in Design,</b> <i>Celaya Technology Institute</i> (1,7), Celaya, Mexico

### Other Experiences —

PyCon Balkan 2019, Belgrade, Serbia
Training: Moderation, Presentation and Visualization
Deep Learning Specialization - Coursera
Conference: Data Natives 2017. Data driven technologies Berlin
Project Management Certification, ATV, Köln
Conference: Data Natives 2016. Data driven technologies Workshop: Learn Python for Data Analysis Berlin

### Publications -

C. Brecher, R. Schmitt, P. Loosen, V. Guerrero, N. Pyschny, A. Pavim, A. Gatej. Self-optimizing approach for automated laser resonator alignment. Optics and Lasers in Engineering 50 2012, 287-292.

### Language Skills ———

Spanish: Native speaker English: Business fluent

German: Fluent

### Programming Languages / Tools \_\_\_\_\_

Very good: python, java, kotlin, jupyter notebooks, gitlab, docker, kubernetes, gira

Good: .NET (C#), SQL, AWS

### Interests \_

Sports (cycling, swimming, jogging) Literature (science, history, philosophy); Traveling Mensa.org Member

Cologne. May 29<sup>th</sup> 2020

### **Annexes**

- Projects description
- **❖** Recommendation letter: Deutsche Telekom Hallo, Magenta!
- \* Recommendation letter: Atlas Copco / Leybold
- Certificate: Scrum Foundation
- Certificate: Certified Project Manager

### **Projects description**

# Freelance Software Developer Germany

Germany 5/2019 –

- ❖ Deutsche Telekom. "Hallo, Magenta" Voice Assistant.
  - Microservices development on Python, Java and Kotlin, these are part of a complex system that interprets natural language.
  - Development of a phonetic/fuzzy module/algorithm to help matching ASR transcriptions to the most possible target. python, java, kotlin, scrum, SAFe, ci/cd, Jira

### Software Engineer – in the Intelligent Products team Leybold GmbH, Cologne 6/2017 – 5/2019

Design and development of a cloud-based data collection strategy.

Data coming from a number of sensors installed in machines connected through an IoT Platform.

- REST API Development in Python using flask and django
- Data Model design and Databases implementation
- Deployment of APIs and Databases to AWS
- ❖ Machine learning models development and clustering analysis
  - Linear Models, Neural Networks, Clustering Algorithms python, flask, django, scikit-learn, keras, pandas, numpy, git, ci/cd, aws

# Freelance Software Developer Germany

*Germany* 9/2016 – 5/2017

- Integration of Industrial Cameras and Development of Image Processing Scripts for automation applications MVTec Halcon, Beckhoff
- Integration of Industrial cameras and Image Processing Software in C# Applications MVTec Halcon, C#, different camera vendors



#### DTAG, P&I, INNOVATION HUB

T-Online-Allee 1, 64295 Darmstadt, Germany axxessio GmbH Kurfürstenallee 5 53177 Bonn

WE ARE: DTAG, GHS, TECHNOLOGY & INNOVATION / Innovation HUB

your contact: Nicolas Walter Stepanek tel. number: +49 6151 58 - 37792

DATE: 06/12/20

SUBJECT: Confirmation of Excellence - Successful project with Mr Vicente Paul Guerrero Lule

Dear Sirs,

We are pleased to confirm that we worked together with Mr Vicente Paul Guerrero Lule (Axxessio GmbH) in 2020 to provide voicified communication services like voicemail or telephony on a smart speaker.

During our project with Mr Guerrero Lule we were delighted by his support. Our customers and we are very happy that he has delivered in budget, time and quality. During our project we found him to be extremely helpful, committed to the task, intelligent and able to work hard. He has proved to be a very good colleague in our team, the kind of person who not just starts a project but always completes them.

We are confident that the experience and knowledge gained by Mr Guerrero Lule in our international project will be for his further benefit.

We would like to thank Mr Vicente Paul Guerrero Lule personally for his work and wish him all the best for the future. We are looking forward to continue our partnership with Axxessio GmbH.

On behalf of

Nicolas W. Stepanek

Senior Manager Technical Innovation / Product Owner Voicified Communication

Product Management Chapter

N. Stepand

#### **LEGAL ENTITY**

Deutsche Telekom AG, GHS

Authorized representatives:

Timotheus Höttges Reinhard Clemens Niek Jan van Damme Thomas Dannenfeldt Dr. Christian P. Illek Dr. Thomas Kremer Claudia Nemat FriedrichEbertAllee 140

53113 Bonn, Germany District Court of Bonn HRB 6794 Registered Office Bonn VAT ID No. DE 123475223 Joeri Coeckelbergs Manager Intelligent Product Atlas Copco Industrial Vacuum Division joeri.coeckelbergs@leybold.com +49 (0) 171 199 3502

Dear Sir or Madam,

It's my pleasure to recommend Vicente Guerrero as a solid software engineer with keen interest and knowledge in machine learning topics.

Vicente has worked in my team for nearly 2 years as an external consultant. Together we have worked on several projects, but he was mainly focusing on machine learning and AI topics within the team. During this time I can say, I was able to get to know him quite well. Strong determination to achieve results, a hands-on approach and a very likeable social character would describe him very well.

Vicente has shown good software engineering work together with project managing skills. During this project his core task was developing a machine learned algorithm to predict certain variables in our machinery. The work he performed was well documented, well-structured and he thoroughly analyzed the problem before starting with the development of the algorithm. This enables him to learn new skills quite fast.

He also had to manage many other stakeholders, including lab personnel or suppliers. With his good people/social skills and a good joke here and there, this has proven to be no problem for Vicente. He will manage to get things done.

With his good project approach, social skills and a good drive to achieve results, I believe Vicente could really become a key asset for everyone looking for a good software engineer for machine learning and AI topics. If you have any more questions or if you would like to have a chat about Vicente, please feel free to contact me

Kind regards,

Joeri Coeckelbergs

Sumbahy

10/04/2019





### ZERTIFIKAT

Die TÜV SÜD Akademie bescheinigt, dass

Vicente Paul Guerrero Lule geboren am 02.11.1985 in Celaya, Mexiko an der Prüfung

## Foundation in agile project management according to SCRUM

nach den Anforderungen der TÜV SÜD Akademie GmbH – Zertifizierungsstelle für Personal, mit Erfolg teilgenommen hat.

Das Zertifikat "Foundation in agile project management according to SCRUM" nach Richtlinien der ITEMO weist Kenntnisse in agilem Projektmanagement nach. Dem Zertifikat liegt das Verständnis für die SCRUM-Theorie (gemäß SCRUM Guide™) zugrunde. Es bestätigt grundlegendes Wissen zur SCRUM-Philosophie, den Ereignissen, Regeln, Rollen, Artefakten und ihren Beziehungen und Wechselwirkungen sowie zur Durchführung von SCRUM-Projekten. Eine Vertiefung des Erlernten durch praktische Übungen hat stattgefunden.

Zertifikatsnummer 1612#312602637 Köln, 30.12.2016

Jürgen Merz Geschäftsführer TÜV SÜD Akademie GmbH

Harald Koelln Prüfungsmanagement der TÜV SÜD Akademie GmbH



### Herr Vicente Paul Guerrero Lule

geboren am 02.11.1985, hat vom 12.09.2016 bis 01.02.2017 im Rahmen des General Management Programs

der ATV GmbH in Köln den Titel

# Certified Project Manager

erworben und die Prüfungen wie folgt bestanden:

Projektmanagement, MS Project: (Gewichtung 1)

Note 2 / 81 Punkte

BWL, Controlling: (Gewichtung 1)

Note 1/96 Punkte

Projektarbeit: (Gewichtung 2)

Note 1/98 Punkte

Erstellung eines Projekthandbuches unter Anwendung von MS-Project. Entwicklung, Dokumentation und Präsentation eines Projektplanes am realen Praxisbeispiel

Gesamtergebnis:

Note 2 / 93 Punkte

Köln 01.02.2017

Karin Steiner Niederlassungsleitung ATV GmbH Köln

100-95 Punkte = 1 • 94-80 Punkte = 2 • 79-65 Punkte = 3 • 64-50 Punkte = 4 • 49-0 Punkte = 5 nicht bestanden





### ERFOLG DURCH NEUE PERSPEKTIVEN

Nutzen Sie unsere Erfahrungen

# General Management Program Project Manager

### Zertifikatslehrgang der ATV GmbH

in Kooperation mit dem INSTITUT FÜR MARKETING UND MANAGEMENTENTWICKLUNG IMM centour PARTNER DER HOCHSCHULE FÜR ANGEWANDTE WISSENSCHAFT MÜNCHEN

### **SEMINARINHALTE**

#### Projektmanagement

Grundlegende Rahmenbedingungen und Zielsetzungen des Projektmanagements, Terminologie und Methodik der Projektplanung, projektorientierte Ablaufplanung (Netzplantechnik), Anwendung von MS Project, Ressourcenmanagement, Mehrprojekttechnik, Projektcontrolling und Berichtswesen

#### Betriebswirtschaftslehre

Projekte aus bilanzieller Sicht, Kosten- und Erfolgsrechnung von Projekten, Bewertungsverfahren langfristiger Projekte, BWL Fallstudie, Business Planning- von der Geschäftsidee zur Umsetzung unter Berücksichtigung von Markt, Chancen und Risiken, Kosten und Finanzierung, Projekte finanzieren, Fundraising, Förderprogramme, Projektanträge

### Selbst- und Zeitmanagement

Ziele klar definieren, planen und ein optimiertes Zeitmanagement effizient strukturieren und fristgerecht umsetzen

### Marketingmanagement

Marktorientierte Unternehmensführung und strategische Planung, Entwicklung von anwendungsorientierte Unternehmens- und Marketingkonzepten

### Rhetorik, Präsentation

Freie Rede, Argumentation, Gesprächsführung und überzeugende Präsentationen, Verhandlungstraining

### Persönlichkeitstraining

Teamtraining, Führungstraining, Moderation, persönliche Marketingstrategien

### Projektarbeit

Entwicklung und Dokumentation eines praxisbezogenen Projektplans unter Anwendung der Software MS Project, Projektbeschreibung, Ablaufplan, Ressourcenplan, Kostenplan

> ATV GmbH Bernhard-Feilchenfeld-Straße 11 50969 Köln

Telefon 0221.93 64 550 Telefax 0221.93 64 55 11 koeln@atv-seminare.de